# 亮子，給介紹一下你今天的老搭檔
Liang, introduce us your partner today.
# 前輩的前輩
My master's master.
# 老前輩
Old Master
# 孔老是中國的老大師烹飪界的
Master Kong is a master Chinese Chef.
# 今年八十多嵗了
He is already over 80 years old.
# 老國寶。專門做麵點
Old man. He is known for his pastries skills.
# 今天是大年初一吃餃子
Today is the first day of the lunar new year. We are going to eat dumplings.
# 我是無冬立夏使涼水
I typically use cold water to make the dumpling dough.
# 因爲使熱水可以快，但是容易皴
Although using hot water can accelerate this process, the dumplings may easily become "cun".
# 什麽叫皴呢
What is “cun”?
# 就是上面皺了
It is when dumplings get wrinkled.
# 開始和麵
Let's make the dough first.
# 您也沒有秤也沒有杆的就直接往裏倒
Master Kong isn't using any scale for measurement.
# 這是靠經驗有兩下子
It is all because he is so experienced.
# 咱們就是一斤面二兩半的水
500g flour with 150g water.
# 軟硬適中，一定要揉透了，醒透了
Not too soft, not too hard. We have to knead and ferment the dough thoroughly.
# 像拔疙瘩湯似的
It's like making dough-drop soup.
# 今天咱們三叔盤道小號正式開始了
Today, San Shu's starts his second channel.
# 希望你們都喜歡
Hope you will like it!
# 我一看老爺子這速度，我得趕緊，來吧
I have to hurry up. Master Kong is so fast.
# 老爺子講究，咱幹活得講究霎利
Master Kong says, you gotta do it fast.
# 今天拿的俄羅斯麵粉
We are using Russian flour today, which is very pliable.
# 筋度很强，我們看看老爺子今天能不能把這面和好
Let's see if Master Kong can still make a good dough out of it.
# 把這餃子包好
And make delicious dumplings.
# 你看著小桌子擦的利利整整
See, the table is so clean.
# 老馮得練刀工了
Feng, you have to practice your knife skill.
# 我有點緊張
I am a little nervous.
# 傳統的話是講究，
Traditionally we stick to the "rules"
# 頂刀使點勁，走
we use the tip of the knife to cut meat.
# 叫老爺子比劃一下
Let Master Kong do it.
# 你看
See?
# 嘿，看見沒
Wow. See?
# 再切成丁
Then, dice them.
# 我來
Let me do it.
# 這叫斬肉
This is called cleaving.
# 好可以了，吃餡啊講究手工剁，機器出來的味不好
It's done. Homemade dumpling stuffing is more delicious that made by machine.
# 是吧，爲什麽呢，它在過程中加熱了
Right? Because it gets heated up in the process.
# 老馮，你切的是海米嗎。海米
-Feng, are you chopping dried shrimps? -Yes.
# 開始先放鹽
We add some salt first.
# 一斤肉咱就先個五克鹽
500g meat, we add 5g salt.
# 來點生抽
Some light soy sauce.
# 今天這肉粘特別新鮮
The meat is so sticky and fresh.
# 來點海米水
Some dried shrimp water.
# 看見沒有，你別急
See? Don't rush.
# 姜水和海米水同時都可以放
We can add ginger water and dried shrimp water at the same time.
# 好，再來點
A little more.
# 鮮香全齊了
Everything is ready!
# 好，怎們再下裏點姜
Ok, let's put in some ginger.
# 怎麽樣黏糊勁上來了吧
It's getting sticky.
# 拿油封上
Add some vegetable oil to seal it.
# 如果怎們家裏吃如果這色要嫌淺咱來點老抽
If the color is too light, you can also add some dark soy sauce.
# 韭菜是最難切的
Chinese chives are the hardest to chop.
# 兩個火柴棍
Two matches.
# 您看成不成
Master, is it good?
# 好
Perfect!
# 吃一個用心做的餃子
If you want the dumplings to be good.
# 那就要用心去做每一個步驟
Then you have to pay attention on every step.
# 把韭菜放上以後，
After we add in the chives,
# 倒裏點油
we add some vegetable oil as well.
# 再來點香油，咱給它封上
Finally, we add some sesame oil to seal it.
# 爲什麽封上呢，韭菜很嫩，這冬天容易出水
Why? Because otherwise water will leak out of the chives.
# 香油這是少而精才香
Add just a little bit of sesame oil.
# 跟拍您孫子屁股蛋子似的
It's like slapping your grandson's butt.
# 今天看三叔帥不帥
Is San Shu handsome today?
# 過年了
It's lunar new year.
# 推拉推拉，不能生拉
Push and pull. Don't use brute force.
# 您動作慢點
Master, can you do it slower?
# 揪了多少個劑子
How many sub-agents have you made?
# 今天揪了三十個。我給您數數看看是不是三十個
30. Wait, let me count.
# 看老頭説不説實話
I wonder if master is lying.
# 四十三個，這老頭想自己偷吃是十個
43? Master, you want sneak out the extra 10?
# 四十個
That's 40.
# 哈哈哈
Hahaha.
# 老頭，講講這是什麽東西
Master, tell us what this is.
# 這是一根棗木頭，棗核擀麵棍
This is Chinese date wood, a date rolling pin.
# 這是我師傅給我的，一百一十年
My master gave this to me. It's been 110 years now.
# 心裏頭想起師傅
It reminds me of my master.
# 不管是包餃子還是做什麽，一定要用心
Not just making dumplings, you have to do everything diligently and attentively.
# 看見沒有，這棗核使的，一二三四五
See, one, two, three, four, five.
# 一個皮五下
One dumpling wrapper takes five strokes.
# 最後關鍵在這呢，放胡椒粉
This is the key part: Adding ground pepper.
# 家庭版元寶餃
Homemade "Yuanbao" (Chinese ingot) Dumplings.
# 餡兒大點，合適就行這手一貼
We can add a generous amount of stuffing.
# 這手一貼
Close the hands together.
# 我看著您手法了
I see how you did that.
# 我一般都這麽樣擱
I usually put the dumpling like this.
# 腚朝上
The bottom faces up.
# 動作慢一點
Can you do it slower, master?
# 看見沒，兩手一推，這一合，鬆手
Push, close, release.
# 三叔給表演一個
San Shu will show us how to do it.
# 抹完以後，還有一什麽動作
What do I do next?
# 這手得背過來，這手一推
We have to flip this hand, and push the wrapper with the other hand.
# 這手過來
This hand comes to the other side.
# 你看見沒有，出來了
See, it's done.
# 這叫什麽啊孔老
What do you call this, Master Kong?
# 看見沒有，他還鎖邊呢
See, he is sealing the sides.
# 知道嗎，鎖這邊叫繩子，一邊還不會呢
This is called rope seal. Not many people can do this.
# 過去老北京必須要會這鎖邊
In the past, you have to learn this in Beijing.
# 這是單邊，還有雙邊，還有蘇荷子
This is single edge. There is also double edges, and Su He Zi.
# 我要下餃子了
I will boil the dumplings now.
# 煮餃子呢，必須蓋蓋
Remember to close the lid.
# 今天大年初一吃餃子要提起精神
We are eating dumplings on the first day of the Lunar Year New Year.
# 點三次水
Add some water for three times.
# 怎們煮到什麽時候合適呢
How long should we boil them?
# 肚子鼓起來
When they start to swell.
# 我就用大盤子上餃子了
I will use the large plate.
# 透徹，不要渾湯
You want the cooking liquid to be clear.
# 別一下煮兩份，一定一次一份
Don't put too many dumplings at a time.
# 瞅著就是跡象
Looks so auspicious.
# 我不讓你們了，這麽好吃的東西我自己先來
Looks so good. I want to try this first.
# 先給年輕的老的后吃
The youngsters eat first, then the elders.
# 先來個餃子吃咯
Let me try a dumpling.
# 有顆粒感肉嫩
You can tastes all the ingredients, and the meat is so tender.
# 就是一個圓圓的餡在裏邊
It is like a meatball inside.
# 蝦仁
Shrimp.
# 我就願意吃剛出鍋的
I love the dumplings when they just come out of the pot.
# 這叫寬條大煮
This is called Kuan Tiao Da Zhu
# 祝您新年愉快
Happy Lunar New Year!
# 新年快樂
# import ending.sbv 0:05:43.700